Emmanuel Egomson - Web/Software Developer

Email: fegomson@gmail.com Mobile: (405) 212 6644 Address: 15400 Crown at Lone Oak Road, Edmond, OK, 73013

Profile

Experienced front-end software developer based in Edmond/Oklahoma City area. A solution-driven professional excelling in highly collaborative work environment. I have helped businesses and charities with my skillset and ability to learn programming languages and frameworks on the fly. Started out as a graphic designer and my passion for user interface design fueled my curiosity to learn how software work and communicate hence honing my software development skills. Proficient in technologies like HTML5, CSS3 (CSS variables, Sass, Styled Components), JavaScript, JSX, ReactJS, React Native, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Firebase, SQL, REST API, CMSs and a lot more.

Key Technical Skills

- 5 years experience with HTML5, CSS3, media queries, CSS frameworks with demonstrable experience with Bootstrap, JavaScript both with and without frameworks like jQuery and Zepto, Ajax and a solid understanding of object-oriented programming, SPAs and the MVC pattern.
- 2 years experience with ReactJS, NodeJS and MongoDB
- 5 years experience with Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop & Illustrator)
- eCommerce/payment gateway integrations with demonstrable experience of working with Stripe,
 PayPal (Standard and Pro) and WorldPay
- API integration work with demonstrable experience of working with the APIs of MailChimp,
 Campaign Monitor, Contentful, SportsRadar, RecipeAPI, Mandrill and YouTube.
- Experience provisioning and maintaining Linux servers with solid command line knowledge and experience with Git, npm and other package managers and utilities
- Ability to administer Apache, MySQL, PHP, OpenSSH and other services
- SSL certificate installation and management

Experience

2017 - present: OAA Study Company (Web Developer - Remote)

- Use various technologies, including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Laravel (PHP), WordPress,
 WooCommerce to create and optimize corporate applications.
- · Design, implement and monitor applications for continuous improvement and integration.
- Optimize Images, scripts and other web assets for speed and performance.
- Create eye catching and functional digital design concepts across various platforms to strengthen company brand and identity.
- Determine coding requirements for site creation, including e-commerce capability and specialized scripts.
- · Provide end-user training for website maintenance and updating.

2019 - 2020: BaseHost.com (Web Developer/Support Engineer - Remote)

- · Zendesk Ticketing System, Chat and Email.
- RDP (Remote Desktop Protocol) and System Support
- Configuration and support in WHMCS, Plesk Onyx, Office365, AWS, Status Cake and New Relic infrastructure.
- Troubleshooting network communication, software, and user account.
- · WordPress development and technical support

2016 - 2017: Greenwich Media - Web Developer

- Converted design assets into component-based HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Leveraged strong understanding of WordPress core to manipulate admin and theme components.
- Installed required plugins and additional coding to fit final design and functionality requirements.
- Collaborated with Project Manager on project specifications, strategy and execution to build new WordPress pages and update existing ones.
- Created and updated re-usable code libraries to streamline WordPress development cycle.

2015 - 2016: Dobox.tv - Web Developer

- Developed user-oriented visuals and features using front-end languages, including HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap Framework and jQuery/JavaScript.
- Completed full redesigns of existing websites to improve navigation, enhance visuals and strengthen search engine rankings.
- Conceived and built optimized landing pages in HTML, CSS and JavaScript including with mobile first approach and strategy.
- Collected, defined and translated user requirements into project designs and implementation plans.
- Tested websites and performed troubleshooting prior to deployment.
- Planned and engineered RESTful web services to manipulate dynamic datasets.
- · Used various technologies, including Laravel and Codelgniter to optimize application.
- Used programming capabilities in PHP, SQL and JavaScript and other libraries as needed.

2013 - 2015: PriceCheck - MIH Internet Africa - Web Content Manager

- Central point of contact for all content matters.
- Optimized web content according to SEO using HTML, CSS where applicable.
- Used content management systems to analyze website traffic and user's engagement metrics.
- · Developed editorial calendar and ensure content team is on board.
- · Liaised with content editors to ensure brand consistency.
- · Managed user generated content and editing accordingly.
- Worked with development team to ensure that product feed (XML/JSON format) issues are being resolved.
- · Created weekly and monthly reports on content matters.
- Integrated product feeds of over 60 online stores in 1 month.

Education

B.Tech. Biochemistry - Yaba College of Technology